Guide to the Quentin Anderson Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Quentin Anderson Papers,
1935-2003
[Bulk Dates: 1960-2000].
Anderson, Quentin, 1912-2003.
19 linear feet (33 document boxes, 7 index card boxes)
Columbia University. Rare book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
5410361
MS#1434
The papers document the life and work of author, Columbia University professor, and literary critic, Quentin Anderson. This collection contains his personal and professional correspondence, his writings and research notes, documentation of his professional involvements, and some personal materials.
History
Quentin Anderson, literary critic, cultural historian, and professor emeritus, began his long relationship with Columbia University as a student in 1934, after a brief enrollment at Dartmouth. Anderson received his B.A. from Columbia in 1937, then matriculated to Harvard, obtaining his M.A. in 1939. He returned to Columbia to begin teaching in the Department of English and Comparative Literature in 1939, earning his Ph.D. in 1953, attaining full professorship in 1961. In recognition of his exceptional service to the University, Anderson was appointed the Julian Clarence Levi Professor in the Humanities Emeritus in 1978. Upon his retirement in 1981, Anderson continued to be actively involved in his field, both as an author and as a participant in several scholarly organizations.
Anderson was born in 1912 in Minnewaukan, North Dakota, the eldest son of author and playwright Maxwell Anderson. The Andersons bought a house in Rockland County, New York, and the family traveled back and forth between there and a home in Manhattan. As a young man, Anderson gained experience in the theater, working on a few of his father's plays as an assistant stage manager and acting in minor roles. After a marriage to Margaret Pickett ended in divorce, Anderson married Thelma Ehrlich in 1947. He had one daughter, Martha, and two sons, Maxwell and Abraham
While an undergraduate at Columbia, Anderson studied with Lionel Trilling and Jacques Barzun as a student in their colloquium on great books. These initial mentors would later become colleagues and lasting friends. While at Harvard, Anderson studied under F.O. Matthiessen and Perry Miller, both renowned scholars in American literary and historical criticism. This experience, coupled with his earlier exposure at Columbia to Romantic and Victorian literature, helped define Anderson's primary research interests. Trilling, a sponsor of Anderson's dissertation, was an especially influential force; Anderson touched on many of the same themes and subjects as Trilling in his scholarly work. Anderson came to be considered a leading authority on 19th century American literature and culture; his research had a particular emphasis on the American authors Henry James, Ralph Waldo Emerson, and Walt Whitman. Much of his work focused on literary figures and the formation of cultural identity in 19th century America. Anderson examined the work of American authors in light of their European antecedents, while also considering the cultural influences that help define an individual's identity. His first book, The American Henry James (1957), explored the family and work of the novelist. His second, The Imperial Self (1971), studied James, Emerson, Whitman, and their contemporaries, and the impact of their works on American literature and culture. Anderson's last book, Making Americans: An Essay on Individualism and Money (1992), examined a wider range of American authors, considering the extent to which cultural history influenced the American literary experience. In addition to his three books, Anderson contributed scholarly essays and book reviews to numerous journals and publications, including The New York Times Book Review and the Times Literary Supplement.
Anderson's roles as author and critic did not prevent him from taking an interest in his students and the University; he was actively involved in campus affairs throughout his career at Columbia. He served as the English Department's representative in Columbia College from 1961 to 1969, and as chairman of the Joint Committee of Disciplinary Affairs in 1968, formed in response to the campus uprising that spring. Anderson's profound intellect coupled with his towering physique was said to intimidate some of his students. He was at once imposing and welcoming, characteristics that led one student to remark in a student course guide that Anderson was "one of the most pompous, friendly men" on campus. Yet, it is clear that he was genuinely committed to their academic and professional success. Several of his former pupils went on to become accomplished academics, and Anderson maintained friendly and professional ties with many of them as they transformed from student to colleague.
Anderson remained a revered member of the academic community throughout his lifetime. He was regularly invited to deliver lectures and participate in discussions at academic institutions and conferences both in the United States and abroad. During the 1960s, he was the recipient of two Fulbright grants which allowed him to accept invitations to act as a visiting professor at two universities overseas, and consequently participate as a guest lecture at institutions across Europe. Anderson was granted a senior fellowship by the National Endowment for the Humanities in 1973-1974, and was awarded a fellowship at the National Humanities Center in 1979-1980. He became a fellow of the New York Institute for the Humanities in 1980, continuing his involvement with NYIH until 2000. One of the lasting legacies of Anderson's time at Columbia is the Lionel Trilling Seminars. Anderson, a close friend of both Lionel Trilling and his wife Diana, was a member of the founding committee that established the lecture series in 1976, the year after Trilling's death. The Lionel Trilling Seminars, a bi-annual event that serves as a forum for intellectual discussion, continues to attract the participation of renowned scholars. Anderson remained actively involved on the seminar committee, even after his retirement. It was one of the many contributions that characterized his career. A festschrift, Emerson and His Legacy, that celebrated those contributions and academic achievements was published in Anderson's honor in 1986.
In the last years of his life, Anderson revisited two subjects that were of personal and professional significance during his youth and at the beginning of his career. In 2000, he performed in a theater production celebrating the centennial of the composer Kurt Weill, a family friend and collaborator of his father Maxwell Anderson. It was a chance for Anderson to relive his experiences of performing onstage while reminiscing about his childhood as he recounted memories of Weill's visits to his childhood home. At the same time, Anderson was working on what would be his last published work, a scholarly essay entitled, "Why R.P. Blackmur Found James's Golden Bowl Inhumane." Here, Anderson returned to the subject of his dissertation and his first major work: Henry James. The essay, published in 2001, added further proof of Anderson's expertise on the American author and provided an appropriate final note to the end of a long and distinguished career. Anderson died two years later in 2003.
Scope and Content
The Quentin Anderson Papers provide a record of Anderson's academic and professional life from 1935 until his death in 2003. The first two series of Anderson's correspondence and writings make up the bulk of the collection, and provide insight into Anderson's various roles as a serious intellectual, celebrated colleague, and admired mentor. Formats include correspondence, typewritten and printed items, and written research notes on both letter-size paper and index card files. The third series documents Anderson's professional career at Columbia University and within the literary community through correspondence, printed materials, and his own notes in preparation for class lectures. The final series holds items of personal significance such as journals, a record of his Broadway performance in his later years, and materials gathered by his wife Thelma Anderson, which are related to his death and memorial service.
Arrangement
Arranged in four series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1937-2003
Series II: Writings, 1937-2001
Subseries II.1: Manuscripts and Essays, 1945-2001
Subseries II.2: Introductions and Reviews, 1949-1996
Subseries II.3: Other Writings, 1937-1990
Subseries II.4: Notes, 1957-1997
Series III: Professional Career, 1935-2002
Subseries III.1: Columbia University, 1935-2001
Subseries III.2: Professional Involvement, 1965-2002
Subseries III.3: Teaching and Lecturing Abroad, 1962-1987
Series IV: Personal Materials, 1937-2003
Subjects
Columbia University.; Lionel Trilling Seminars.; Anderson, Quentin, 1912-2003.; Anderson, Maxwell, 1888-1959.; Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882--Criticism and interpretation.; James, Henry, 1843-1916--Criticism and interpretation.; Trilling, Lionel, 1905-1975.; Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892--Criticism and interpretation.; American literature--History and criticism.; Criticism--United States.; Education--Study and teaching--United States.; Literature and society.; Articles.; Card files.; Correspondence.; Drafts (literary).; Essays.; Journals.; Lectures.; Manuscripts (literary).; Notes.; Reviews.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Some folders in Subseries III.1: Columbia University, 1935-2001 are restricted. Please see container list for details.
Acquisition
Mrs. Thelma Anderson, Gift, June 2004 (with a subsequent addition in May 2005).
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1937-2003
  Series I is comprised of correspondence between Anderson and his professional and personal contacts, including mentors, colleagues, students, family, and friends. Many files also contain examples of the professional work of the individual, such as essays or reviews. The correspondence chronicles how Anderson's numerous professional relationships became long lasting friendships over time. They also illustrate the many friendships Anderson established with his students that continued long after they graduated from Columbia, some of whom eventually became his colleagues. This series is arranged alphabetically by the individual's last name.
  - Aaron, Daniel, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abrams, Meyer H., 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allen, Fredrick, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anderson, Brom, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anderson, Charles, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Anderson, Craig, 1992-1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anderson, Maxwell L., 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arieli, Jehoshua, 1982-2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bacigalupo, Massimo, 1974-2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baltzell, Jocelyn, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Barber, C.L., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Baris, Sharon, 1977-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Baris, Sharon, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Barker, Paul, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1948-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bateson, Gregory, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bayley, John, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bazelon, David T., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Beichman, Arnold, 1968-1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bell, Daniel and Pearl, 1961-2003 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bender, Tom, 1984-1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bentley, Eric, 1948-1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bercovitch, Sacvan, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bercovitch, Sacvan, 1971-2001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Berlin, Isaiah, 1977-1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Berman, Marshall, 1960-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Berman, Paul, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bernstein, Gene, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bernstein, Ulrich, 1939-1948 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Berson, James, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Berthoff, Warner, 1964-1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Betsky, Seymour, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Blackford, Staige D, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Blair, Hugh, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Blau, Joseph L., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bleich, David, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bloom, Harold, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bogart, Leo, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Boyer, Robert, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Boynton, Robert, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Braudy, Leo, 1980-2001 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Bromwich, David, 1986-2003 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Brown, Alan and Beatrice, 1948-1986 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Brown, Fredrick, 1977-2001 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Calabrese, Stephen, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Caponigri, A. Robert, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Capouya, Emile, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Chambers, Glen, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Chapman, John Jay, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Chase, Richard and Frances, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Chesler, Pearl, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chiappe, Andrew, 1949-1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Christiansen, Rupert, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Clifford, James, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Collins, Philip, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Conant, Oliver, 1973-1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cox, James, and Clark, James W., 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Cunliffe, Marcus, 1967-1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dalton, Elizabeth, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Davis, Robert Gorham and Hope, 1963-1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dearborn, Mary, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Delany, Paul, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Delbanco, Andrew, 1987-2003 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - De Morelos, Leonardo and Mary-Elizabeth, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - DeMott, Benjamin, 1966-1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Denby, David, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Derrida, Jacques, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Dewey, John, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Dick, Henry, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Dickstein, Morris, 1977-2001 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Dimock, Wai-Chee, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Donadio, Stephen, 1978-1998 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Donn, Anthony, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Dowling, William, 1988-1999 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Donoghue, Denis, 1967-1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Douglas, Ann, 1977-1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Douglas, Mary, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dupee, F.W., 1945-1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dydo, Ulla E., 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Eliezer, Rabbi, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Epstein, Joseph, 1976-1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Erskine, Bill and Nancy, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Everett, Charles, 1952-1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Evett, Robert, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fisch, Harold, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Flanagan, Tom and Jean, 1959-1965 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fletcher, Angus, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Flint, R.W., 1973-1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Fisher, Philip, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Fogel, Aaron, 1978-2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Frankel, Charles and Helen, 1937-1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - French family, 1941-1965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Fuchs, Daniel, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Geertz, Clifford, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Gibbons, Bernard, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Gold, Ivan, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Goldman, Arnold, 1972-1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Goldman, Michael and Elinor, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Gonnaud, Maurice, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Goodheart, Eugene, 1988-1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Goodheart, Pat, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Goodman, Paul, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Goodman, William, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Gordon, Lyndall, 1972-2001 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Gould, Timothy, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Graff, Gerald, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Graubard, Stephen, 1975-1999 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Gregory, Dorothy, 1970-2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Greisman, Judith, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Grenander, M.E., 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Gross, John, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Grossman, Elsa and Jim, 1952-1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Gutman, James, 1935-1941 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Gutwirth, Marcel, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Haack, Susan, 1992-1995 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Habegger, Alfred, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Habermas, Jurgen, 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Hart, Jeffrey, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Hassan, Ihab, 1963-1967 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Hays, Paul and Elinor, 1959-1976 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Heinzelman, Kurt, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Hellman, Lillian, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Hickman, Albert, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Higham, John, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Hodgart, Matthew and Pat, 1967-1996 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Hoggart, Richard, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Hollander, John, 1977-2001 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Hollis, C. Carroll, 1983-1987 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Horowitz, Floyd R., 1961-1992 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Hovde, Carl, 1960-2001 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Howard, Richard, 1953-2002 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Howe, Irving, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Howell, Nell (Mrs. Theodore), 1971 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Hubbard, Howard, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Hughson, Lois, 1976-1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Jamieson, Michael, 1988-1995 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Javitch, Daniel, 1976-1988 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Jemie, Onwuchekwa, 1962-1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Johnston, Kenneth, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Judt, Tony, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Kahn, Sholom J., 1975-1994 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Kazin, Alfred, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Kenyon Review Editors, 1946-1949 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Kermode, Frank and Anita, 1976-1993 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Klingenstein, Susanne, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Koch, Kenneth, 1995-2002 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Kornhauser/Fiske, 1950-1954 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Kribs, Roba, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Kristol, Irving, 1962-1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Krupnick, Mark L. undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Kuhns, Richard, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Langenfeld, Robert, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Lazarsfeld, Paul, 1948-2001 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Leach, William, 1988-1994 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Leary, Lewis, 1966-1984 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Leavis, R., 1946-1948 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Leese, Marianne B., 1996 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Leibowitz, Herbert, 1968-1995 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Lenya, Lotte, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Lenzer, Gertrud, 1965-1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Lewis, RWB, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Lindberg, Kathryne, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Llovett, Jordi, 1985-1997 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Locke, Richard, 1971-1973 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Loewenberg, Robert J., 1980 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lowe, John, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Lowell, Robert, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lucke, Elmina, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Lynen, John F., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - McAleer, John, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - McKitrick, Eric, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - McNeil, Paul, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - McWilliams, Wilson Carey, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Magnet, Myron, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Maher, Donald, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Mailer, Norman, 1968-1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Marcus, Gene, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Marcus, Steven, 1960-1976 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Matthiessen, F.O., 1938 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Mazzeo, Joseph, 1961-1988 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Mednick, Elizabeth, 1980-1988 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Meli, Franco, 1982-1985 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Menand, Louis, 1994-1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Merton, Robert K., 1975-2003 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Miller, Perry, 1939-1940 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Mills, Charles Wright and Ruth, 1946-1974 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Morris, John, 1963-1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Morrison, Susan, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Moynihan, Patrick, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Nathanson, Tenney, 1983-2002 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Nelson, Benjamin, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Nobbe, George, 1951-1963 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - O'Hara, Daniel, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Ohsima, Jin, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Olney, James, 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Orser, Loyd, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Orth, Ralph, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Osborn, Robert, 1968-1978 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Packer, Barbara, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Parker, William, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Paynter, John, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Pease, Donald, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Phillips, William, 1984-1989 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Poirier, Richard, 1972-1999 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Poor, Anne, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Pyne, Stephen J., undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Railton, Stephen, 1972-1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Raines, Theron, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Reagan, Ester and John P., 1984-1995 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Rice, Philip Blair, 1945-1957 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Ricoeur, Paul, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Riesman, David, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Riskin, Myra, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Rizzuto, Anthony, 1978-1999 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Rosenthal, Michael, 1976-2001 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Rosenwald, Lawrence, 1978-2002 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Rosenweig, Saul, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Rotenberg-Moses, Deborah, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Rothen, Marshall, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Rothenberg, Albert, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Rothstein, Edward, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Rovit, Earl, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Rowe, Joyce, 1983-2001 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Rust, Richard, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Said, Edward, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Samet, Thomas, 1984-1985 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Schless, Howard, 1963-1967 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Schneiderman, Howard, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Seavey, Ormond, 1979-2000 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Sennett, Richard, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Shell, Marc, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Shivers, Alfred S., 1970-1983 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Shreve, Shannon, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Silver, Allan, 1978-1981 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Simpson, David, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Simpson, Lewis, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Smith, Henry Nash, 1974-1986 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Smith, M. Brewster, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Smoler, Fred, 1985-1995 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Sollors, Werner, 1981-1986 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Solomon, Barbara, 1979-1985 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Sontag, Susan, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Stade, George, 1964-1967 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Stanford, Donald E., 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Stern, Fritz, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Stevenson, Diane, 1986-1993 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Strout, Cushing, 1980-1996 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Sugarman, Fredric, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Susens, Millicent, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Tanner, Tony, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Taylor, William, 1988-1990 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Teres, Harvey, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Tennyson, G.B, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Thompson, John, 1960-2001 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Thompson, Kenneth, 1971-1973 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Thompson, Raplh, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Trask, Timothy, 1981-2001 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Trilling, Lionel, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Trow, George, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Troy, William, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Tuttle, Peter, 1999-2003 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Van Doren, Mark and Dorothy, 1971-1995 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Vidan, Ivo, 1966-1974 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Villicana, Eugenio, 1958-1983 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Vincent, J.R., 1979 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Voegelin, Eric, 1971-1973 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Vossenkuhl, Dr. Willi, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Waddell, R.C., 1952-1953 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Waggoner, Hyatt Howe, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Wang, Arthur, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Ward, Aileen, 1981-1997 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Warren, Joyce, 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Watson, George, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Weber, Donald, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - West, Michael, 1974-1978 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - White, E.B., undated (Box 13, Folder 22)